<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My personal space</title>
    <link>https://SimY4.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My personal space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SimY4.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hi there 👋</title>
      <link>https://SimY4.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SimY4.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Father of 2, FP enthusiast, Software Engineer, Geek&#xA;Currently Principal Software Engineer, Atlassian&#xA;Playing solution architect and tech lead roles for the new cloud platform development from inception to production roll out.&#xA;Specialized in AWS, DynamoDB, SQS, Kinesis, EC2, ALB&#xA;Languages, Java (17 years), Scala (9 years), Kotlin (8 years), Clojure (1 year), Rust (1 year), Javascript Typescript (17 years), Typescript (2 years)&#xA;Occupation Aug 2016 - Sep 2022 Senior Software Engineer, Atlassian</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Stringly Typed</title>
      <link>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/005-avoiding-stringly-typed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/005-avoiding-stringly-typed/</guid>
      <description>There’s this saying that you shouldn’t have String as your function input unless you expect three volumes of War and Peace as valid input. So unless it’s your case and you want to improve your codebase to be more precise in type signatures, I invite you to discuss one possible option. I’ll use the following API as our case study:&#xA;interface EmailSender { void sendEmail(String from, String to, String subject, String body); } there’s an obvious ambiguity in the type signature here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consistency: There and Back Again</title>
      <link>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/004-consistency-there-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/004-consistency-there-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>What is Consistency token? Link to heading A consistency token represents the state of a resource or entity at a given point in time. It is opaque to consumers, returned in the ETag header by data modifying APIs. Consumers may cache some of these tokens in a request-local or short-term cache when coordinating a number of calls to control the consistency they require via a custom Event-Stream-State request header(s) with the following format (as per standard RFC definition):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Compiling Scala in Gradle project</title>
      <link>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/003-cross-compiling-scala-in-gradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/003-cross-compiling-scala-in-gradle/</guid>
      <description>It is quite common and widely spread practice for Scala projects to cross-compile and publish several artifacts for multiple versions of Scala compiler. As a rule, for the purposes of creating several versions of one artifact teams using SBT where this feature is avaiable right out of the box and can be configured in a couple of lines. But what if we want to cross-publish our Scala project the same way without using SBT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monads Explained</title>
      <link>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/002-monads-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/002-monads-explained/</guid>
      <description>Referential transparency Link to heading Referential transparency is a nice property of pure functional programming languages that allow us to reason about the behaviour of our programs. It guarantees that all expressions are always evaluating to the same result in any context. What it gives to the programmer is an ease of equational reasoning about any pure program as they used to do it in math.&#xA;2 + (2 * 2) === 2 + 4 === 6 &amp;#34;Hello&amp;#34; + &amp;#34; &amp;#34; + &amp;#34;world&amp;#34; === &amp;#34;Hello &amp;#34; + &amp;#34;world&amp;#34; === &amp;#34;Hello&amp;#34; + &amp;#34; world&amp;#34; === &amp;#34;Hello world&amp;#34; List(1, 2, 3) ++ List(4, 5, 6) === List(1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6) g(f(a)) === (g compose f)(a) If you think about it, most of the modern compilers (non-FP included) can already do some optimisations for referentially transparent code fragments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here you are!</title>
      <link>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/001-here-you-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SimY4.github.io/posts/001-here-you-are/</guid>
      <description>Hi, there.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this that means that you&amp;rsquo;ve ended up in my personal blog. Welcome! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep it short and interesting for both of us.&#xA;In the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve got fascinated by the topic of pure functional programming. I was lucky enough to see it being applied in real-world projects, I learned a lot from people practising it at their everyday work. And today, I believe I grasped enough knowledge on this topic for me to share it with you as a series of educative blog posts.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
